Mark D. Levine Papers VHP2006/9
CCSU Veterans History Project
Mark D. Levine Papers
Bulk, 1981-1996
1981 - 1996, 2006
VHP2006/9
CCSU Veterans History Project
50.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details Mark D. Levine's experience serving with U.S. army as a medic during Persian Gulf War. The collection contains video of an oral history interview, service documents, and photographs.
Levine, Mark D., (Mark David), 1953 -
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Biographical/Historical note
Mark D. Levine joined the U.S. Army in 1981, at the age of 31. He was a ninth grade Physical Education teacher at the time. He went to basic training at Fort Benning, Ga., and then onto Paratrooper School. He also went to school to be a medic. After schooling he was assigned to an infantry platoon as a line medic. Levine was part of the invasion of Grenada, where he cared for injured soldiers in the jungle. He then worked out of Fort Bragg, Ga., until he enlisted with Special Forces as a medic in 1986. Because of Levine's medical and paratrooper training, he was chosen as a member of FAST (forward airborne surgical team), one of the first groups of medical personnel that would parachute in to provide medical support on the front lines. He performed duties in FAST during the uprising in Panama and during hurricane recovery efforts in St. Croix. After these assignments, Levine went on to Saudi Arabia during the 1st Gulf War, where he trained as a ranger, and then applied that training with FAST during Operation Desert Storm, where the team worked throughout Kuwait and Kuwait City. After Levine's time in the Middle East, he was sent to Germany, and then to Colorado. It Colorado he supervised a small hospital, and it was there that he found out that his neck was crushed from a prior jump. Although, he wished to remain in the military for an additional five years, Levine was discharged in 1996 for medical reasons. After his discharge he worked as a private practical nurse, and used the G.I. Bill to further his education.
United States. Army. Airborne Division, 82nd.; United States. Army. Mountain Division, 10th.; United States. Army. Ranger Battalion, 3rd.; Fort Bragg (N.C.); Germany; Grenada; Kuwait; Military nursing -- United States -- History; Panama Canal (Panama); Persian Gulf War, 1991 -- Personal narratives, American; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Saint Croix (V.I.); Saudi Arabia
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/9.I
  - Diploma awarded for Airborne Course completed at United States Army Infantry School, Fort Benning, Georgia, Mar. 24, 1983; VHP2006/9.I.1
  - Certificate awarded for Airborne Corps Monitor’s Intrusion Course completed at Fort Bragg, North Carolina, Jul. 5, 1983; VHP2006/9.I.2
  - Certificate awarded for Task Force 2-504 Cold Weather Operations Course Fort Wainwright, Alaska, Dec. 15, 1983; VHP2006/9.I.3
  - Diploma awarded for Leadership Development Course, Jul. 24, 1984; VHP2006/9.I.4
  - Announcement for Army Commendation Medal, Jul. 17, 1984; VHP2006/9.I.5
  - Certificate of Promotion to rank of Specialist Five, Mar. 1, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.6
  - Certificate of Achievement for Attaining high level of proficiency in Field Medical Functions, Mar. 15, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.7
  - The Army Achievement Medal for distinguished service, Jul. 16, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.8
  - The Army Achievement Medal for distinguished service, Sep. 5, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.9
  - The Good Conduct Medal for exemplary behavior, Sep. 27, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.10
  - The Army Achievement Medal for meritorious service, May 8, 1986; VHP2006/9.I.11
  - Certificate of Training for Practical Nurse Course, Jun. 25, 1986; VHP2006/9.I.12
  - Medical Department Regiment Certificate of Affiliation, Jul. 27, 1986; VHP2006/9.I.13
  - Announcement for The Army Achievement Medal, Oct. 27, 1986; VHP2006/9.I.14
  - Diploma for Practical Nurse Course, Jul. 7, 1987; VHP2006/9.I.15
  - The Army Commendation Medal for meritorious service, Dec. 30, 1988; VHP2006/9.I.16
  - Army Commendation Medal for Meritorious service, Jan. 3, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.17
  - Announcement of promotion to Staff Sergeant, May 4, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.18
  - Course Completion Certificate for Operation Room Specialist course, May 1, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.19
  - Certificate of Achievement for Jumpmaster Course at Fort Bragg, NC, Jun. 9, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.20
  - Announcement for the Army Good Conduct Medal, Jul. 13, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.21
  - Announcement of amendment for the Army Commendation Medal, Jul. 18, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.22
  - Announcement of amendment for the Army Achievement Medal, Aug. 3, 1989; VHP2006/9.I.23
  - Award announcement for Senior Parachutist Badge, Feb. 20, 1990; VHP2006/9.I.24
  - Recommendation for award, Mar. 1, 1990; VHP2006/9.I.25
  - Certificate of Achievement for Air Movement Operations course at Fort Bragg, NC, Apr. 6, 1990; VHP2006/9.I.26
  - Certificate for service during “Operation Desert Storm”, March 1991; VHP2006/9.I.27
  - Memo stating the completion of Jumpmaster Refresher course, June 1991; VHP2006/9.I.28
  - Emergency Medical Technician — Basic Certificate, Aug. 15, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.29
  - Certificate for Emergency Medical Technician - National Registry course, Aug. 16, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.30
  - Certificate of Training for Emergency Medical Technician, Aug. 16, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.31
  - The Good Conduct Medal for exemplary behavior during active military service, Sep. 27, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.32
  - The Army Commendation Medal for Meritorious service, Oct. 1, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.33
  - Diploma for AMEDD NCO Basic course, Oct. 10, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.34
  - Announcement for Good Conduct Medal, Nov. 15, 1991; VHP2006/9.I.35
  - Memo stating completion of Drop Zone Support Team Leader course, Jan. 13, 1992; VHP2006/9.I.36
  - Announcement for Combat Medical Badge, Jun. 8, 1992; VHP2006/9.I.37
  - Certificate of Training for “Documenting Special Legal Situations” Course, Mar. 1, 1993; VHP2006/9.I.38
  - Certificate of Training for Unit Alcohol And Drug Coordinator Course, Mar. 26, 1993; VHP2006/9.I.39
  - Diploma for AMEDD NCO Advanced course, Jul. 14, 1993; VHP2006/9.I.40
  - Certificate of Training for “Thoughts About Nursing” course, Sep. 13, 1993; VHP2006/9.I.41
  - Certificate of Training for Wardmaster Development Course, Sep. 30, 1994; VHP2006/9.I.42
  - Certificate of Appreciation for Outstanding Achievement as an EFMB Instructor, May 19, 1995; VHP2006/9.I.43
  - Certificate of Training for Medical Assessment Treatment, Aug. 15, 1985; VHP2006/9.I.44
  - Mark Levine’s Honorable Discharge, Nov. 19, 1996; VHP2006/9.I.45
  - Form PA 8547, Pioneer American Insurance Company Processing Verification Form, September 1995; VHP2006/9.I.46
  - Academy of Health Science Transcript, Aug. 25, 1987; VHP2006/9.I.47
  - Interview synopsis, Jan. 18, 2006; VHP2006/9.I.48
- Series II: Multi-Media, VHP2006/9.II
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2006/9.II
    - Mark D. Levine at unidentified memorial site, n.d.; VHP2006/9.II.1
    - Mark D. Levine at unidentified memorial site, n.d.; VHP2006/9.II.2
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2006/9.IIb
    - Oral history interview with Mark D. Levine, Jan. 18, 2006; VHP2006/9.IIb.1; Hurst, Eileen (Disk DVD VHP2006/9, Box VHP Interview 2006)